marcelrominger

portfolio

rominger.net be.net/romingermarcel

contact

Istidsgatan 19 LGH 0404 90655 Umeå Sweden

+46 735 350199 rominger.marcel@gmail.com

personal

10/27/1988 Male German

languages

German native English fluent Swedish beginner French beginner

education

09/14-06/15 M.Sc. Human-Computer Interaction and Social Media Umeå universitet, Sweden My thesis is about embodied interaction. A combination of eye-tracking and speech recognition in order to control a system. The goal is to remove tangible artifacts from a user's perception.

2008-2012

B.Sc. Computer Science Hochschule für Technik Stuttgart, Germany My thesis was about an innovative real-time based residential power scheduling scheme for smart grids. The implementation was done in JAVA.

experience

2013-2014

Verivox GmbH

Software systems engineer

As part of a multicultural scrum team, I helped to maintain and improve Germany's best and most popular comparison website of the years 2012, 2013 and 2014. We worked closely together with the UX team. Together we attended sprint kickoffs, daily scrum meetings, retrospectives, general project planning or were supporting each other in daily business tasks. We developed using C#, ASP.NET MVC, JavaScript(jQuery), HTML, CSS, Visual Studio and Subversion. We applied techniques like test-driven development, MVC, inversion of control, dependency injection, unobtrusive JavaScript, REST and AJAX.

2012-2013

Thales Deutschland GmbH

Software engineer

One part of my work was to improve an already existing internal software tool. The work involved VBA, XML as well as Subversion. Contextual inquiry was applied in order to improve the user experience and user interface. I describe my role as in-house support for the users as well as maintenance and improvement of the software tool.

The other part of my work involved working in a scrum team. We developed a completely new internal tool using C#, AutoCAD .NET, WPF, MVVM, Visual Studio and Subversion. The work involved creating the user interface, specifying the system architecture as well as implementing and testing.

2011-2012

Bombardier Transportation GmbH

Mannheim, Germany

Heidelberg, Germany

Stuttgart, Germany

Working student - System architecture

My work involved assisting a system architect in daily business tasks. I created UML diagrams with Enterprise Architect and was administrating a Linux server as well as a MySQL database.

2010-2011

IBM Deutschland Research & Development GmbH

Böblingen, Germany

Intern - Quality assurance

I was part of an international team. I developed and validated functional and regression tests for IBM DB2 and IBM DB2 Optim Performance Manager. The tests were created with the help of JAVA, IBM Rational Functional Tester and an internal IBM DB2 SQL query workload tool.

skills

Agile Scrum, Kanban

Design Human-centered, Personas, Scenarios, Evaluations, Wireframes, Rapid proto-

typing, Lo-Fi and Hi-Fi prototypes, Questionnaires, Interviews, Contextual In-

quiry, Designing with blends

Hardware Arduino

Object oriented analysis, design and programming

OS Mac OS X, Windows, Linux

Programming JavaScript(Angular, jQuery, Processing), HTML, CSS(Bootstrap), C#, ASP.NET

MVC, WPF(MVVM), JAVA, Python and Ruby(on Rails), C/C++/, ABAP, Android,

Assembler

Tools Adobe After Effects & Photoshop, Axure, Balsamiq

interests

Personal: I played soccer in a team for about ten years when growing up and still follow soccer in general excessively. Other than that, I like cycling, hiking, being outside and enjoying nature or reading different kinds of literature.

Professional: Over the years that I have worked, I have developed an interest for prototyping itself as well as creating and shaping user experience. This is also the main reason I moved to Sweden, to study Human-computer Interaction and Social Media.

profile

I am open minded. I have the ability to quickly adapt to changing situations. I am able to identify and troubleshoot issues. I have experience in working in multicultural teams and high performance environments. There is still a lot for me to learn, but I like to learn and I am a fast learner. I am a self-starter and try to keep up with state of the art. I consider myself as a multi-talented person, being able to get a lot of different things done.